[
  {
    "question": "DDL commands are used to:",
    "options": [
      "Retrieve table data",
      "Manipulate data insert/update/delete",
      "Define or modify database structure",
      "Grant user privileges"
    ],
    "answer": "Define or modify database structure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is TRUE?",
    "options": [
      "DELETE removes table structure",
      "TRUNCATE is a DML command",
      "DROP removes both data and structure",
      "REMOVE is to delete the data"
    ],
    "answer": "DROP removes both data and structure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which DDL command is used to modify the structure of a table?",
    "options": [
      "UPDATE",
      "ALTER",
      "MODIFY",
      "INSERT"
    ],
    "answer": "ALTER"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a DML command?",
    "options": [
      "INSERT",
      "CREATE",
      "DROP",
      "SELECT"
    ],
    "answer": "INSERT"
  },
  {
    "question": "DML commands are used to?",
    "options": [
      "Retrieve table data",
      "Create or Modify database structure",
      "Insert, update, delete the data",
      "Grant or revoke permissions"
    ],
    "answer": "Insert, update, delete the data"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which clause is mandatory in UPDATE statement?",
    "options": [
      "WHERE",
      "SET",
      "FROM",
      "ORDER BY"
    ],
    "answer": "SET"
  },
  {
    "question": "DELETE command without WHERE clause will:",
    "options": [
      "Delete table",
      "Delete all rows",
      "Delete one row",
      "Give error"
    ],
    "answer": "Delete all rows"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which command is used to retrieve data?",
    "options": [
      "GET",
      "FETCH",
      "SELECT",
      "READ"
    ],
    "answer": "SELECT"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the BETWEEN operator do?",
    "options": [
      "Checks equality",
      "Checks range of values",
      "Checks NULL",
      "Checks pattern"
    ],
    "answer": "Checks range of values"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which operator is used to combine multiple conditions?",
    "options": [
      "IN",
      "AND",
      "BETWEEN",
      "LIKE"
    ],
    "answer": "AND"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which operator returns TRUE if any one condition is TRUE?",
    "options": [
      "OR",
      "AND",
      "NOT",
      "IN"
    ],
    "answer": "OR"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which query selects employees from dept 10 and 20?",
    "options": [
      "WHERE dept_id = (10,20)",
      "WHERE dept_id IN 10,20",
      "WHERE dept_id IN (10,20)",
      "WHERE dept_id = 10 AND 20"
    ],
    "answer": "WHERE dept_id IN (10,20)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of IN operator?",
    "options": [
      "Check NULL values",
      "Compare range",
      "Compare multiple values",
      "Pattern matching"
    ],
    "answer": "Compare multiple values"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of LIKE operator?",
    "options": [
      "Compare numbers",
      "Check range of values",
      "Search for patterns in text",
      "Check NULL values"
    ],
    "answer": "Search for patterns in text"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which SQL query selects employees whose names start with ‘A’ and contain ‘n’ anywhere after the first letter?",
    "options": [
      "WHERE emp_name LIKE '%An%'",
      "WHERE emp_name LIKE 'A%n%'",
      "WHERE emp_name LIKE 'A_n%'",
      "WHERE emp_name LIKE 'An%'"
    ],
    "answer": "WHERE emp_name LIKE 'A%n%'"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of this query? SELECT emp_name FROM emp WHERE emp_name LIKE '%n%';",
    "options": [
      "Names starting with n",
      "Names ending with n",
      "Names containing n",
      "Names exactly n"
    ],
    "answer": "Names containing n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of this query? UPDATE emp SET salary = salary + 5000 WHERE emp_id = 101;",
    "options": [
      "Updates all employees salary 5000",
      "Updates emp_id column with salary 5000",
      "Increases salary of emp_id 101 with salary 5000",
      "Gives error"
    ],
    "answer": "Increases salary of emp_id 101 with salary 5000"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of this query? SELECT emp_name FROM emp WHERE dept_id = 20 AND salary > 30000;",
    "options": [
      "Dept 20 employees only",
      "Employees with salary > 30000",
      "Dept 20 employees with salary > 30000",
      "All employees"
    ],
    "answer": "Dept 20 employees with salary > 30000"
  },
  {
    "question": "A table EMP has 5 columns. One column SALARY has a DEFAULT value. Which INSERT statement is VALID?",
    "options": [
      "INSERT INTO emp VALUES (101,'Anu',10,30000);",
      "INSERT INTO emp (emp_id, emp_name, dept_id, salary) VALUES (101,'Anu',10,30000);",
      "INSERT INTO emp (emp_id, emp_name, dept_id, location) VALUES (101,'Anu',10,'Hyd');",
      "INSERT INTO emp VALUES (101,'Anu',10,'Hyd',DEFAULT);"
    ],
    "answer": "INSERT INTO emp VALUES (101,'Anu',10,'Hyd',DEFAULT);"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which query correctly prints the salary+bonus column name in result?",
    "options": [
      "SELECT salary+bonus FROM emp;",
      "SELECT salary+bonus AS finalSalary FROM emp;",
      "SELECT salary AS bonus FROM emp;",
      "SELECT bonus AS salary FROM emp;"
    ],
    "answer": "SELECT salary+bonus AS finalSalary FROM emp;"
  }
]
